抱歉  我还得要一阵
Sorry, I'm gonna be a while.
打扰  你知道还有别的...
Excuse me, do you know where there's another...
谢谢  谢谢
Ah, thank you. Thank you.
住手
Stop!
天呐
Oh, my god.
桑迪
Sadie.
打911
Call 911!
里克  要有魅力  但别太过分了
Now, Rick, be charming but not too charming.
这就像让超人别那么"超"
That's like asking superman not to be too super.
有魅力怎么了
What's wrong with being too charming?
没什么不好  只是为凶杀案作证时就不合适了
Nothing, except when you are testifying in a murder trial.
有魅力的人让陪审团觉得自信
Look, being charming tells the jury that you're confident,
但如果做过头
But being too charming tells
他们会觉得你想操控他们
them that you're trying to be manipulative.
我懂了  这就是你从不让我为我们的
Oh, I see. This is why you never had me testify
案子作证的原因
in any of our cases.
你是嫉妒我的魅力
You're jealous of my charm.
我是说真的  别自大
I'm serious, okay? Don't get cocky.
这是你第一次出庭作证
This is the first time you'll be testifying in court,
作证有时很让人紧张
and it can get nerve-racking.
我会没事的  尤其据传
I'll be fine, especially since word on the street
辩护律师根本没本事
is the defense lawyer is a total hack.
是吗  是谁
Oh, yeah? Who is it?
斯坦·诺瓦克
Stan Novak.
"精神集中不过三秒"斯坦吗
"Short attention span" Stan?
那人自己做盘问时都会找不到北
That guy gets lost in his own cross examinations.
嗯  那你会没事的
Yeah. You will be fine.
可惜你是没法看我作证了
Too bad you won't be there to see me in action.
-我会去的  -那样好吗
- No, but I will. - Is that wise?
我们明面上还是分手状态啊
I mean, publicly, aren't we still supposed to be separated?
这可是桑迪·比克曼的凶案审判
This is the Sadie Beakman murder trial we're talking about.
她的伊拉克报导
Her reporting from Iraq
成就了很多美国人对伊战的看法
shaped the way many Americans saw the war.
而且这还让她得以创办自己的网站
Plus it gave her the profile to launch her own news website.
作为为她的凶杀案结案的分局警监
And as captain of the precinct that closed her murder case,
如果我不去才奇怪呢
it would be odd if I didn't show.
那我们就该想个秘密信号
Then we should come up with a secret signal.
我们的暗号  来表明
A little thing just between the two of us that says,
"我爱你"
"I love you."
我觉得那就有点...
Oh, you know, I think that would be a little...
-你需要纸巾吗  -不是
- Do you need a tissue? - No,
这是我的秘密"我爱你"手势
this is my... that's the secret "I love you" signal.
-喜欢吗  -摸鼻子吗
- Do you like it? - Rubbing your nose?
-嗯  -是啊  真浪漫
- Yeah. - Yeah, that's really romantic.
总之  我得走了
Anyway, I got to go.
我要去见维克拉姆  回头庭上见
I'm meeting Vikram. I'll see you at the court.
我也爱你
Yes, I love you, too.
监视卡莱布·布朗
Where are we on surveilling Caleb Brown
将他与洛克塞特联系起来进展如何
and connecting him to LokSat?
跟上周
Exactly where we were last week
上上周  上上上周的情况一样
and the week before that and the week before that.
就是毫无进展吗
So nowhere?
我们公设辩护人办公室的那位目标
Our target at the public defender's office
就像个超级反派  没有弱点
is like a super villain... no weaknesses.
得了  那是不可能的
Oh, come on. That's not possible.
是吗  因为我和茜茜已经试过了
Sure about that? 'cause Cee Cee and I have tried every pos--
-等等  什么  茜茜是谁  -没谁
- Wait, what? Who's Cee Cee? - No one.
你是给你的电脑起了个女生名字吗
Did you give your computer a girl's name?
你不了解我的生活
You don't know my life.
此前我从未为此感到如此庆幸呢
I've never been happier about that until this moment.
我受够了跟大家撒谎
Look, I am tired of lying to everyone.
我想要回我的生活
I want my life back,
鉴于你都跟你的电脑发展恋情了
and given your new relationship with your computer,
你也需要回归自己的生活了
it's time you get yours back, too.
我们赶紧想出卡莱布·布朗的弱点吧
So let's figure this out. What is Caleb Brown's weakness?
这将是我参与过的最简单的案子
This is gonna be the easiest case I have ever tried.
你为什么如此肯定
How can you be so sure?
被告有一堆逮捕记录
The defendant has a history of arrest
全是因为扮成酒席承包人抢劫高端住宅
for robbing high-end houses while working as a cater waiter.
桑迪·比克曼抓了她个现行
Sadie Beakman caught her in the act
被告为逃跑而杀了她
and the defendant killed her in order to get away.
这不都是只有旁证推测吗
Isn't that all circumstantial?
是的  所以幸好我有你
Yes, which is why it's a good thing I have you...
一名目击证人
an eyewitness.
被告真的该接受我提出的认罪协议的
The defendant really should've taken that plea deal I offered.
是啊  她为什么没接受
Yeah. Why didn't she?
你觉得他们会如何抗辩
What do you think their defense is gonna be?
别去想那个
Don't concern yourself with that.
不管他要如何扭曲事实
No matter how he tries to spin the facts,
你要坚持陈述自己所看到的
you stick with what you saw.
妮娜·奥基弗杀了桑迪·比克曼
Nina O'Keefe killed Sadie Beakman.
这是被害人的家庭
The victim's family.
是啊  我记得
Oh, yes, I remember.
很高兴再见到你们
Nice to see you again.
很抱歉是因为这样的事
Sorry it's under such terrible circumstances.
是啊  我们也是
Yeah. Us, too.
你们还好吗
So, how are you holding up?
有时还好  但更多时候不好
Some good days, more bad.
我们似乎无法翻篇
We can't seem to get over it.
我妻子在伊拉克跟部队
You know, my wife spent two years embedded
潜伏了两年都毫发无伤
with troops in Iraq and not a scratch.
却死在曼哈顿一个派对上  真是没道理
And then a party in Manhattan. Doesn't make sense.
我们会为她主持正义的
Well, we're gonna get her justice.
-马库斯  -你来了太好了  警监
- Marcus. - Hey. Glad you could make it, captain.
我怎么听说你约会蕾妮了
So, um, what is this I hear about you asking Lanie out?
不不  你误会了
No, no, no, no. You got that wrong.
是蕾妮约的我
Lanie asked me.
真的吗  我...
Really? That's what I...
妮娜
Nina.
我是卡莱布·布朗  是公设辩护人办公室的
My name is Caleb Brown from the public defender's office.
我今天将代理你
I'll be representing you today.
卡莱布·布朗怎么来了
What is Caleb Brown doing here?
问得好
That's a good question.
全体起立  庭审开始
All rise! This court is now in session.
有请尊敬的法官葛洛丽亚·沃考特
The honorable judge Gloria Wollcott presiding.
请坐
Be seated.
哎呀  卡莱布·布朗先生
Well, well, well, Mr. Caleb Brown.
虽然很高兴在我的庭上见到你  但诺瓦克先生呢
As lovely as it is to see you in my courtroom, where's Mr. Novak?
法官大人
Your honor,
诺瓦克先生的妻子昨晚早产了
Mr. Novak's wife went into premature labor last night.
天呐
Oh, no.
母婴平安
The baby's fine, as is the mother,
但诺瓦克先生显然不能来了
but obviously Mr. Novak is unavailable,
所以公设辩护人办公室叫我来接手
so the public defender's office asked me to take over.
-你已经了解案情了吗  -是的  法官大人
- And you're up to speed on the case? - Yes, your honor.
另外  我今早还格外下了一番功夫
Plus I did a little work on my own this morning.
-有任何反对吗  维勒先生  -没有  法官大人
- Any objections, Mr. Weller? - None, your honor.
那么继续吧  法警  请陪审团
Then let's proceed, shall we? Bailiff, bring in the jury.
公诉人传罗杰·马特斯  法官大人
The people call Roger Masters, your honor.
桑迪善良  周到  慷慨
Sadie was kind, thoughtful. She was generous.
我很清楚  我们是20多年的朋友
I would know. We were friends for over 20 years.
她创办自己网站之前
I was her cameraman back when she was still
还做通讯记者时  我是她的摄影师
a news correspondent before she started her website.
谢谢你  马特斯先生  没有其他问题了
Thank you, Mr. Masters. No further questions.
凶案是发生在你的联体别墅  是吗
So, the murder took place at your townhouse, is that correct?
是的
I'm afraid so.
我和妻子主持了一场鸡尾酒派对
My wife and I hosted the cocktail party
你的委托人在派对上杀了桑迪
where your client killed Sadie.
你看到我的委托人杀人了吗
Did you see my client kill her?
没有
No. No, I did not.
壁炉拨火棍刺穿了胸腔
The fireplace poker punctured the ribcage
割伤了比克曼太太的主动脉
and nicked Mrs. Beakman's aorta,
导致她大量失血并最终死亡
causing massive blood loss and her eventual death.
比克曼太太是当场死亡的吗
Did Mrs. Beakman die immediately?
她的伤势会在
It would've taken 5 to 10 minutes
5到10分钟内致死
for her to succumb to her wounds.
帕里什医生  比克曼太太是不是很痛苦
Dr. Parish, would Mrs. Beakman have been in much pain?
是的  非常痛苦
Yes. Excruciating pain.
没有其他问题了  法官大人
No further questions, your honor.
被告当时在逃
The defendant was on the run
-直到我和搭档  -直到我和搭档
- until me and my partner... - Until my partner and I
最终在中央车站逮住了她
caught up with her at Grand Central Terminal.
那么  我的委托人认罪了吗
And... and did my client confess?
没有  她没有录口供
No. She didn't make a statement.
-她只说  -她只说...
- The only thing she said... - The only thing she said
她想叫律师
was that she wanted to speak with a lawyer.
公诉人传唤理查德·卡塞尔
The people call Richard Castle.
请举起右手
Raise your right hand.
抱歉  这才是右手
Oh, sorry. This is the right hand.
你是否发誓说真话  说出全部真话
Do you swear to tell the truth, the whole truth,
-而且只说真话  -是的
- and nothing but the truth? - I do.
卡塞尔先生  您是做什么的
Mr. Castle, what is it that you do for a living?
我是位悬疑小说家
I'm a murder-mystery novelist.
你还做过别的吗
Have you held any other jobs?
是的  我有六年作为平民调查员
Yeah, six years as a civilian investigator
与纽约警局12分局凶案组合作的经历
working with the NYPD, homicides for the 12th precinct.
那么你对破解凶案
So, you're a bit of an expert
是个行家了
when it comes to solving murders?
是的  而我凭这份经验
Yes, and I use that expertise
给我的小说带来真实感
to lend authenticity to my novels.
你是为何会在五个月前的9月14日
Now, what brought you to the home of Roger and Joanna Masters
前往罗杰和乔安娜·马特斯家
on the evening of September 14th five months ago?
乔安娜·马特斯赢下了一场慈善拍卖
Joanna Masters won a charity auction
赢得了我去她家  私下诵读
to have me come to her home and do a private reading
我次日将出版的
of "Driving Heat," my latest novel,
最新小说《希特袭来》的机会
due to come out the following day.
天呐
Oh, my!
理查德·卡塞尔驾临寒舍
Richard Castle... in my home.
见到你很高兴
It is a pleasure to meet you.
我可喜欢你的书了
Oh, I just adore your books.
妮基·希特  我的偶像啊
I mean, Nikki Heat is, like, my role model.
我爱死她了  -我也是  你太客气了
- I love her. - Me, too. You are too kind.
-你太帅了  -这话我喜欢
- And you are too cute. - Keep talking.
请进吧  请进
Please come in, come in.
这位是我丈夫  罗杰
Like you to meet my husband, Roger.
理查德  见到你很高兴
Richard. Nice to meet you.
-欢迎  -谢谢
- Welcome. - Thank you.
这是
And, uh...
-这是比克曼夫妇  -于是我结识了桑迪·比克曼
- These are the Beakmans. - That's when I met Sadie Beakman.
桑迪  罗伊德和他们可爱的女儿安妮
Sadie, Lloyd, and their lovely daughter, Annie.
-理查德  认识你很高兴  -认识你很高兴
- Richard. Nice to meet you. - Nice to meet you.
你一定认得出桑迪
I'm sure you recognize Sadie
知道她出名的伊拉克战争报道
from her Iraq war news reports,
但她也是比克曼新闻网的所有人和经营者
but she also owns and operates BeakmanReport.com.
见过准被害人后
After meeting the soon-to-be victim,
我也见到了准凶手
I met the soon-to-be killer.
要香槟吗
Champagne?
谢谢各位的到来
Thank you so much for being here.
谢谢邀请我来
Thank you for having me.
抱歉用了这么小的海报  大的用光了
Sorry about the small poster. I ran out of the big ones.
《希特袭来》  此人所著
"Driving Heat," written by...this guy.
"妮基·希特升任
"The last thing Nikki Heat expected
纽约警局警监时  万万没有想到..."
when she received her promotion up to captain of the NYPD..."
诵读结束后  我去用洗手间
After the reading, I needed to use the restroom.
抱歉  我还得要一阵
Sorry, I'm gonna be a while.
于是我便去了楼上的洗手间
So I went to use the facilities upstairs.
住手
Stop!
这时我撞见了被告杀害桑迪·比克曼的场景
That's when I saw the defendant kill Sadie Beakman.
请记录显示目击证人指认了
Let the record reflect the witness has identified
被告妮娜·奥基弗是他所指的女人
the defendant, Nina O'Keefe, as the woman in question.
没有其他问题了  法官大人
Nothing further, your honor.
布朗先生  你方证人
Mr. Brown, your witness.
卡塞尔先生  我不想太占用你的时间
Mr. Castle, I-I don't want to take up too much of your time.
我只有几个问题
I only have a handful of questions.
首先  我的委托人
First... is it possible
是否可能没有杀害比克曼太太
that my client did not kill Mrs. Beakman?
不可能  绝对是她
Oh, no. It was definitely her.
你对当晚的事件记得很清楚吗
And you remember the events of the evening clearly?
因为  我知道你有失忆史
Because I know that you have a history of memory loss.
-反对  法官大人  -这事关可信度
- Objection, your honor. - Goes to credibility.
反对无效
I'll allow it.
卡塞尔先生  2014年5月12日
Mr. Castle, is it true that on May 12, 2014,
你是否曾被至今未查明的人绑架
you were abducted by parties still unknown
8周后才又出现
and then returned 8 weeks later?
是的
Yes.
而且你依然失着忆
And you still have memory loss?
只对那8周失了忆
Only of those eight weeks.
我对你委托人杀害比克曼太太的记忆十分清晰
My memory of your client killing Mrs. Beakman is crystal clear.
你怎么可能确定呢
But how can you be sure?
因为我是目击证人
Because I was an eyewitness.
很高兴你用了这个词
So glad that you used that word.
目击证人
Eyewitness.
卡塞尔先生
Now, Mr. Castle,
你在案发当晚曾诵读
you gave a reading of "Driving Heat"
《希特袭来》
on the evening in question,
这是妮基·希特系列的新书
the continuing adventures of Nikki Heat.
能否为庭上读一小段
Might you humor the court and just give us a short reading?
就读高亮的部分即可  麻烦了
Just the highlighted section, if you please.
"妮基以及每个警察都经常会见到
"Nikki had seen it often, as every cop had.
本来很可靠的目击证人
otherwise-reliable eyewitnesses
搞错或搞混在那些没有
conflate or confuse details that seem indelible
因事件产生创伤的人眼里不可磨灭的细节"
to those not caught up in the trauma of the incident."
据之前的证词
According to previous testimony,
你凭你在纽约警局的经验
you use your expertise with the NYPD
为你的小说增添真实性
to add authenticity to your stories.
是吗
Is that correct?
被告杀了比克曼太太
The defendant killed Mrs. Beakman.
我清楚我看到了什么
I know what I saw.
那么你2015年2月2日也清楚自己看到了什么吗
Just like you knew what you saw on February 2, 2015?
卡塞尔先生  你是否曾向
Mr. Castle, did you give a statement
韦斯切斯特警局的尼利警探作证说
to a Detective Neely of Westchester P.D.
你目睹了伊娃·威特福德的被杀
that you were an eyewitness to the murder of Eva Whitfield
-而她丈夫科尔是凶手  -是的
- and that her husband, Cole, was the killer? - Yes, I did...
-那么科尔·威特福德是凶手吗  -不是
- And was Cole Whitfield the killer? - No.
那么你以前就错过
So you've been wrong before.
那次事件是个陷阱
That incident was a setup.
而比克曼太太的遭遇并非如此
What happened to Mrs. Beakman was not.
我看到被告杀人了
I saw the defendant kill her.
而此人自己的书中
Says the man whose own writings
也提到了目击证人的不可靠性
speak to the unreliability of eyewitnesses,
而且此人过去曾提供过不实证词
a man who has given false eyewitness statements in the past,
还有  此人有失忆史
a man with a history of memory loss.
-马库斯  帮帮他  -如果我能怎么会不帮
- Marcus...help him. - Don't you think I would if I could?
卡塞尔先生  我们假装
Mr. Castle, let's pretend
你是你小说的一个人物
that you're a character out of one of your novels.
那么妮基·希特会认为你是可靠目击证人吗
Would Nikki Heat think that you were a reliable witness?
这个问题太可笑了  她当然会信任我
That is a ridiculous question, and yes, she would.
我真对你失望  卡塞尔先生
I'm disappointed in you, Mr. Castle.
我以为你是最会
I thought you of all people
对我的委托人产生同情的
would be sympathetic to my client.
你自己不就曾被陷害犯下谋杀吗
Weren't you once framed for murder?
那是3XK  是个连环杀手
That... yeah, that was 3XK, the serial killer.
他是跟我有仇
He had a vendetta against me.
那根本是另一码事
That... that was... that was different.
为什么对你就是另一码事  对我委托人就不是
W-why is it different for you but not for my client?
你凭什么那么特别  卡塞尔先生
What makes you so special, Mr. Castle?
帕里什医生证实被害人比克曼太太
Dr. Parish testified that the victim, Mrs. Beakman,
遇刺后还活了5到10分钟
was alive for 5 to 10 minutes after being stabbed
而且当时十分痛苦
and in excruciating pain.
或许我的委托人只是撞见了被害人
Might it be that my client simply came across the victim
而真凶刺伤她后已经逃逸
after the true killer stabbed her and fled?
-但那...  -这可不是你的小说  先生
- But that... - This is not one of your stories, sir!
你不能随你心意编造事实
You do not get to make up the facts as you see fit.
我的委托人在为她的人生争取
Now, my client is fighting for her life
就像你曾与3XK斗争那样
just as you once fought for yours against 3XK.
那么我再问你一次  卡塞尔先生  我委托人
So, now I ask you one last time, is it possible, Mr. Castle,
是否可能并没杀比克曼太太
that my client did not kill Mrs. Beakman?
有可能的
Yes, it's possible. Yes.
是有可能  你有可能错了
Yes, it is possible. Possible that you are wrong.
没有别的问题了  法官大人
Nothing further, your honor.
卡塞尔先生  你可以退下了
Mr. Castle, you may step down.
卡塞尔先生
Mr. Castle.
退下吧
Step down.
都快5点了
It's nearly 5:00.
我们明天继续
We will pick this back up in the morning.
法庭明天上午9点重新开庭
Court is in recess until 9:00 a.m.
过来
Come here.
马库斯  我很抱歉  我不知道怎么回事
Marcus, I'm so sorry. I don't know what happened.
-我被偷袭了  -不不
- I got torpedoed. - No, no, no, no.
你是被抹杀了
You got nuked.
你没事吧
Are you okay?
贝克特  我刚刚毁了整个案子
Beckett, I just blew the entire case.
庭审还没结束呢  是吧马库斯
Well, the trial's not over yet, right, Marcus?
我不骗你  我们现在麻烦大了
Look, I'm not gonna lie to you. We got a serious problem now.
卡塞尔  你刚刚给了陪审团合理怀疑
Castle, you've just given the jury reasonable doubt.
但我们还能做点什么的吧
But there's got to be something we can do, right?
我们得在法庭明早重新开庭前
Well, we have until court resumes tomorrow morning
找到新证据
to find new evidence
或其他目击证人证明妮娜有罪
or another witness who can prove Nina's guilt.
是啊  但你能在不到16小时内
Yes. However, what can you possibly uncover
找到什么啊
in less than 16 hours?
我不知道  但我们得一试
I don't know. But we have to try.
我们还要再翻几次案卷啊
How many more times do we have to go through these case files?
需要多少次就多少次
As many as it takes.
贝克特  我们这里有汪洋大海却没有针
Beckett, we got stacks and stacks of hay here but no needles.
我们得换个策略
I think we need a new strategy.
我真不敢相信我搞砸得多严重
I can't believe how badly I blew it out there.
这都怪我  各位  对不起
This is my fault, guys. I'm sorry.
别那么责怪自己
Don't do that to yourself.
我们都在证人席上栽过跟头
We've all been tripped up on the witness stand.
是啊  我做警员时
True. Back when I was in uniform,
一个辩护律师把我整得五迷三道
a defense attorney got my head so turned around
我居然作证说我逮捕被告时
that I testified the defendant actually kicked my ass
被她踢了屁股
when I tried to arrest her.
这有什么不对
What's wrong with that?
被告是个75岁坐轮椅的老太太
The defendant was a 75-year-old woman in a wheelchair.
我在陪审团面前信誉扫地
I lost all credibility with the jury.
直至今日  我们经过她喂鸟的公园
To this day, we pass the park where she feeds the birds,
她还会偷笑  跟她的护工讲述
she snickers, turns to her nurse, and tells her the tale
她当年拿下我们可怜哈维的故事
of how she got one over on poor old Javi.
露辛达女士  我总有一天能逮到她
Ms. Lucinda... I will get her one day.
但你们有人在谋杀案庭审中搞砸过吗
But have any of you botched your testimony in a murder trial?
是啊
Exactly.
埃斯波  那个露辛达女士的故事
Hey, Espo, that story about Ms. Lucinda...
她到现在还会谈论她让你出丑的故事吗
so she still talks about how she made a fool out of you.
是啊  多谢你给伤口撒盐了  贝克特警监
Yes. Thank you for rubbing it in, Captain Beckett.
各位  我们的策略错了
You guys, we're approaching this wrong.
我们一直在找凶案当时的线索
I mean, we've been trying to find a clue from the murder,
而我们应该找凶案发生后的线索
whereas we should be looking for a clue from after the murder.
是啊  妮娜被捕后就一直被关押
Yes. Nina's been held since her arrest.
她或许跟狱友吐露过什么
She might've confessed something to a cellmate.
我们去把她狱友接来吧
Let's bring Nina's cellmate in.
谢谢你
Hey, thank you.
谢什么
For what?
没有放弃我
For not giving up on me.
你也从没放弃过我  所以
Well, you've never given up on me, so...
卡塞尔  等等
Castle, wait.
这里不行
Uh, not here.
对了  我们分居呢
Oh, right. Separated.
你没事吧  你过敏了吗
Are you okay? Do you have allergies?
不  那是...那个手势
No, that's the... that's the signal. That's the...
对了  你真的该想个更好的
Oh, yes. You really should think of something better.
多可爱啊
It's adorable.
最新美剧下载
www.ZiMuZu.tv
该死  妮娜这张照片不错啊
Damn. That's a good photo of Nina.
我的入狱照  可难看了
You know, in my mug shot, I look like a train wreck.
大概是因为我当时嗑可卡因嗑嗨了
Probably because I was high on crack at the time.
回答问题
Just answer the question.
妮娜有透露任何关于谋杀案的事吗
Has Nina revealed anything about the murder?
有  我偷偷告诉你俩  她有罪的
Yep. Between the three of us, she's guilty as hell.
你知道什么
What do you know?
好吧  布里吉特  你想要什么
Okay, Bridget, what do you want?
姑娘家还能要点啥  警探
Oh, what does any girl want, detective?
让凶手伏法的满足感吗
The personal satisfaction of bringing a killer to justice?
接下来10周
50 bucks in my prison
每周给我的监狱小卖部存50美元
commissary every week for the next 10 weeks.
40美元  5周
40 bucks for 5 weeks.
8周  我不会再低了
Eight, and that's as low as I'll go.
成交  你最好有货真价实的情报
Deal. But you better have some solid information.
说吧  妮娜认罪了吗
Now, has Nina confessed to the murder?
没有
No.
但我知道是她干的
But I know she did it.
妮娜是这样的
Look, here's the deal with Nina.
她是只老鼠  不怎么说话
She's a mouse. Doesn't talk much.
然后有一天  她说出她担心
Then one day she lets slip she's worried
公诉方会发现她的秘密
the prosecution might find out about her secret.
-什么秘密  -没说
- What secret? - Didn't say.
我猜是跟她男友有关
I think it has to do with her boyfriend or something.
什么男友
What boyfriend?
如果妮娜有个秘密男友
If Nina has a secret boyfriend out there,
-她可能跟他说了  -嗯
- there's a chance she confessed to him. - Yeah.
不  我只是想知道
No, I'm just trying to figure out
妮娜被捕时在跟谁约会
who Nina was dating when she was arrested.
我是否跟警方是一伙儿的
Am I working with the police?
-别认  -不不
- No. - No, no.
我是妮娜的高中同学
I went to high school with Nina.
哪所学校  塔夫特吗
What school? Uh...Taft?
喂
Hello? Uh...
妮娜的人
None of Nina's people
是不会帮我们立案起诉她的
are gonna help us build a case against her.
我们得另想办法确认
We're gonna have to figure out a different way
妮娜男友的身份了
to identify Nina's boyfriend.
我做到了  跟我来
I just did. Follow me.
我去查了妮娜的账
So, I went through Nina's financials.
凶案前一晚
It turns out the night before the murder,
妮娜在东格林威治一家酒吧买了酒
Nina bought drinks at a bar on the east village.
这家酒吧已经倒闭了
Now, that bar went out of business.
但隔壁的酒店
However, the hotel next door
有当晚的监控录像
had surveillance footage from that night.
看
Look.
记住  这是妮娜杀桑迪的前一晚
Now, bear in mind, this is the night before Nina killed Sadie.
-妮娜来了  -妮娜的男友在里面吗
- There's Nina. - Is Nina's boyfriend in this?
不是她男友  等着
Not her boyfriend. Wait for it.
是女友
Her girlfriend.
桑迪
Sadie!
是的
Yep.
被害人和凶手有私情
The victim and the killer were having an affair?!
我的声音怎么尖了
Why is my voice so high?
瞧  贝克特
You see, Beckett?
这就是我喜欢12分局的地方
This is why I love the 12th precinct.
你们从不让我失望
You guys never let me down.
这段视频是凶案的新动机
This recording gives you new motive for murder,
而且铁证如山
and it's ironclad.
妮娜和桑迪有私情
Nina and Sadie were having an affair.
她们显然起了争执
Clearly, they were fighting,
妮娜很可能是激情犯罪了
and Nina most likely killed her in a crime of passion.
好了  我会叫我的人
Okay. I will have my people track down
找到酒吧的前雇员
former employees of this bar,
希望其中有人能证实私情的事
and hopefully one of them can corroborate the affair.
好  我会让我的人
Okay, and I'll have my team
跟桑迪的家人朋友联系
touch base with Sadie's family and friends.
或许他们了解
Maybe they can shed some light
这段私情背后的内幕
as to what was behind this little love affair.
瞧  马库斯  你还担心呢
You see, Marcus? And you were worried.
好了  各位  我们找到妮娜的棺材了
Okay, boys, we found Nina's coffin.
现在我们去给她钉死在里面吧
Now let's nail it shut.
我去跟妮娜的雇员谈谈
I'll talk to Nina's employees.
我去找她朋友问话
I'll go talk with her friends.
桑迪在跟那女人出轨
Sadie was having an affair with that woman?
这太扭曲了
That is so twisted.
关起来的门后是什么样谁都不清楚
Well, you never know what goes on behind closed doors.
那么你们对桑迪的婚外情毫不知情吗
So you knew nothing about Sadie's extramarital affairs?
她很擅长保密
She was good at keeping secrets.
那么为什么雇佣妮娜供职的酒席承包公司
Then why hire the catering company that Nina worked for?
是桑迪推荐的
Sadie's recommendation.
她去过一场他们承办的活动
She went to an event that they catered,
说食物很棒
said the food was amazing.
我敢说桑迪和妮娜就那么认识的
I bet that's how Sadie and Nina met.
你说呢  理查德
What do you think, Richard?
很有可能
Entirely possible.
瞧  我就说过我是妮基·希特的大粉丝
See! I told you I was a Nikki Heat fan.
我连思路都想她
I even think like her, too.
-简直不可思议  -是啊
- It's uncanny. - I know.
幸好你把
It's good that you moved
篮球板移到了离别墅远点的地方
the basketball hoop away from the townhouse.
是啊  那东西
Oh, yeah, those things,
就是对盗贼的邀请函
they're just an invitation for burglars to break in.
或是帮助妮娜这样的杀人犯逃跑
Or murderers like Nina to break out.
我们一直把篮球板放在那里  妮娜给搬动了
Well, we always keep the hoop there. Nina moved it.
是啊  我们直到
Yeah, we didn't even realize
凶案发生后第二天才意识到她搬过
that she had until the day after the murder.
你们怎么确定是妮娜搬的
How are you sure it was Nina that moved it?
如果不是她
Well, if it wasn't her,
还能是谁啊
who else could it have been?
莱恩  说句话
Ryan, a moment?
失陪一下
Excuse us.
篮球板被移动
The basketball hoop being moved
说明是事先有预谋
speaks to a premeditative act.
是啊  但我们的理论是
Yeah, but our theory of this whole thing
这是一起激情犯罪  你觉得呢
is a crime of passion. What are you thinking?
我们并不了解全部内情
That we don't know the whole story.
我看到妮娜骑在桑迪身上前这楼上还有别人
Someone else was up here before I caught Nina over Sadie.
告诉我你在开玩笑吧
Please tell me you're joking.
篮球板被移动过这一点很重要
The fact the basketball hoop was moved is significant
因为妮娜是没理由动它的
because Nina didn't have any reason to do it.
凯特  为什么叫我来
Kate... why am I back here?
马库斯  这一点很有道理
Marcus, this is a legitimate concern.
如果不是妮娜动了篮球板  那么是谁  为什么
If Nina didn't move the hoop, then who did and why?
我们别忘了我们所知的  卡塞尔看见了妮娜杀桑迪
Let's stick with what we know. Castle saw Nina kill Sadie.
就是这样
End of story.
我现在已经不百分百确定了
I'm not actually 100% sure about that anymore.
等等  别告诉我
Wait. Don't tell me you're
你信了卡莱布那套荒谬的抗辩
buying into Caleb's ridiculous defense.
里克  你今天在庭上被整懵了  这时有发生
Rick, you got your bell rung in court today. It happens.
卡莱布·布朗是个好律师
Caleb Brown is a hell of an attorney.
你现在得放手了
Now you got to let it go.
你不打算调查吗
So you're not going to investigate?
你看到录像了  她们有私情
You saw the tape. They were having an affair.
这是激情犯罪  妮娜有罪  就这么简单
It's a crime of passion. Nina is guilty, plain and simple.
我们不是得完全确定吗
Don't we have to be sure?
里克  看着我  我确定
Rick, look at me. I'm sure.
-马库斯  或许我们...  -够了
- Marcus, if we could just... - Stop.
这案子容不得
This case cannot afford
你再往别人耳朵里灌输怀疑了
to have you pour any more doubt into people's ears.
听我说  我知道你俩分居了
Listen, I know you two are separated and all,
但你能不能劝劝他
but could you please talk to him?
卡塞尔  你真认为妮娜是清白的吗
Castle, are you sure that Nina's innocent?
我不知道
I don't know.
但比让有罪者获得自由更糟的是什么
But what's worse than letting a guilty person go free?
把无辜之人送进监狱
Sending an innocent one to jail.
好吧
All right.
回家吧  我一会儿再过去
Go home. I'll swing by later.
你不相信你亲眼所见
So you don't trust what you saw?
我现在不确定了
I don't know that I can anymore.
我只是不停在脑海中回放那些画面
I just...keep running it in my head over and over again.
你觉得妮娜只是在帮助那个可怜女人
And you think Nina was just trying to help this poor woman?
妮娜当时背对着我
Nina's back was to me.
我确实没看见致命一击  我
I didn't actually see the death blow. I...
你们得相信我
You got to believe me, you guys.
看起来真的像是她杀的人
I-it really looked like she did it.
我相信你
Mm-hmm. Well, I believe you.
说实话听起来也像妮娜是杀人凶手
It's just honestly it sounds to me like nina killed her.
-我也觉得  -我必须查出真相
- Me too. - I have to find out for sure.
爸爸  那是不可能的
Dad, there's no way to do that.
我明白
I know.
或许有可能呢
Or is there?
我有办法了
I've got it.
我只要做到两点
And I'd only have to do two things.
第一  把庭审延期  我就有机会调查
One, delay the trial so I have a chance to investigate,
第二  我要和妮娜面谈
And two, have a one-on-one conversation with Nina.
妮娜的律师不会同意的
Uh, Nina's lawyer will never allow it.
所以我必须非常聪明
Which is why I'm going to have to be very clever
变通处理
with how I go about this.
我猜你有计划了吧
I take it you have a plan.
你知道我有的  妈妈
You know I do, mother.
我能问是什么计划吗
Might I ask you what it?
我要把自己弄进监狱
I'm gonna get thrown in jail.
什么事
Yes?
早上好  法官大人
Good morning, your honor.
卡塞尔先生  你不能进来
Mr. Castle, you can't be in here.
可是我已经进来了
And yet here I am.
法官大人  昨天我在庭上出糗
Your honor, I was made a fool of yesterday on the stand.
我要维护名声的  所以我想再来一次
I have a reputation to protect, so I would like...A do-over.
再来一次
A do-over?
A do-over.
好吧  我说两点  第一  那太蠢了
Okay, two things. One -- that's stupid.
第二  你跑到我的办公室就很不道德
And two -- your presence in my chambers is highly unethical.
我可以以蔑视法庭为由收押你
I could hold you in contempt of court for this.
我倒想让你试试
Well, I would like to... see you try.
雷吉  请你进来
Reggie, come in here, please.
卡塞尔先生  我知道你和市长的交情
Mr. Castle, I'm aware of your friendship with the mayor,
所以虽然你不配  我还是放你一马
So even though you don't deserve it, I'm gonna let you go.
雷吉  请把他送出大楼
Reggie, escort him out of the building, please.
法官大人  我看你是在哈德逊大学
Oh. Your honor, I see you attended law school
读的法学院
at Hudson University. Mm.
怪不得你的工作做得那么烂
That explains why you're so bad at your job.
你说什么
Excuse me?
你看  大家都知道
Yes, you see, uh, everyone knows
只有罪犯才上哈德逊大学
only criminals attend Hudson University.
我自己在那就破了三起谋杀案
I myself have solved three homicides there.
喂  你好
Hello?
请找葛洛丽亚·沃考特
Gloria Wollcott, please.
我就是
Speaking.
我们是三山安保公司
Yes, this is Tri-Mountain Security calling.
您在康涅狄格州家中的报警器响了
The alarm on your Connecticut home was triggered.
警官刚才报上来的
The officer responded,
很抱歉报告说您家被盗了
And I'm afraid the report is that your residence was burglarized.
什么  我马上就去
What?! Okay, I'm on my way.
我家被盗了
My house has been burglarized.
法官大人  你知道我是谁  有什么本事
Your honor, you know who I am and what I'm capable of doing.
我能帮你抓小偷
I can find those burglars for you.
-怎么抓  -首先我要一份
- How? - Well, first I would need a listing
全体哈德逊大学在校生
of all the Hudson University students
和三州地区毕业生名单
and alumnus in the tri-state area.
好了  够了
Okay, that's it.
蔑视法庭  把他扔到牢里去
Contempt. Have him thrown into a holding cell.
我的审讯五分钟前就该开始了
Hey, my trial was supposed to begin like five minutes ago.
-发生什么了  -法官推迟到了明天
- What's going on? - Judge postponed your trial until tomorrow.
你今天晚上会被送回里克尔斯岛监狱
You'll be transported back to Rikers at the end of the day.
你是怎么进来的
So, what are you in for?
对不起  这不好笑
Sorry, bad joke.
别跟我说话
Don't talk to me.
妮娜  我知道你和桑迪的地下情了
Nina, look, I know about the affair with Sadie.
助理检察官也知道了
The A.D.A. knows it, too.
他会利用这点置你于死地
He is gonna use it to bury you.
你为什么说这些
Why are you telling me this?
我在现场  妮娜  我亲眼看见你了
I was there, Nina. I saw you. I saw you with my own eyes.
我没杀害桑迪  我爱过她
I didn't kill Sadie! I loved her.
你是在现场  但是你看错了
So, yeah, you were there, but you saw it wrong.
那就告诉我  我没看见什么
So tell me what I missed.
我发现桑迪躺在地上  有人已经捅伤了她
I found Sadie on the ground. Someone had already stabbed her.
她呼吸困难  所以我把棍子拔了出来
She was struggling to breathe, so I pulled the poker out.
我是想帮她
I was trying to help her.
那你为什么要跑
So then why did you run?
我知道看起来是什么样  我慌神了
I knew how it looked. I panicked.
那你被警察逮捕的时候为什么不告诉他们
Why didn't you tell that to the police when they caught you?
别闹了  我以前也被抓过  被害惨了
Please. I've been arrested before, and I got screwed over.
知道为什么吗  因为那些警察没人相信我
You know why? Because none of the cops believed me.
我不会再犯同一个错误
I wasn't gonna make the same mistake twice.
-至少告诉你的律师了吧  -当然
- Did you at least tell your lawyer? - Of course.
我把那事全告诉原来的公辩律师了
I told my original public defender all about the affair,
他说这只能给人杀人动机的感觉
But he said it'd just come across as motive.
太"出人意料"了  果然如此
Surprise, surprise. It did.
那场争斗是怎么回事
What about the fight?
你和桑迪在酒吧门口的争斗
The fight you had with Sadie outside the bar
谋杀案发生的前一晚
The night before the murder?
不是什么重要的事
It was nothing.
妮娜
Nina...
Nina.
我觉得你说的是实话
I think you're telling the truth,
但是你不告诉我事情的全部我也帮不了你
but I can't help you unless you tell me the whole story.
是因为好几件事情争执起来的
The fight was about a couple things.
我受够了偷偷摸摸
I was sick of sneaking around,
但是桑迪太偏执了  因为她过去
But Sadie was all paranoid because she had been caught
和别的男人偷情被抓到过
cheating with other guys in the past.
别的男人
Other guys?
所以你是她的第一个
So, you were her first...
同性恋人
Lesbian?
是的  有问题吗
Yes. Is that a problem?
我不介意  查查我的搜索历史你就明白了
No, not with me. You should check my search history.
但你说你们是因为好几件事情吵起来的
But you said you were arguing about a couple of things.
真正惹怒我的是桑迪让我
What really pissed me off was that Sadie asked me
在鸡尾酒宴会上做些事情
to do something at that cocktail party.
她让你做什么
What did she ask you to do?
把罗杰·马特斯的空酒杯拿给她
Bring her Roger Masters' empty champagne glass.
宴会的主人罗杰·马特斯吗
Roger Masters the host?
-她要他的空杯子干什么  -她没说
- Why would she want his empty glass? - She wouldn't say.
这真的让我火冒三丈
And that really got me fired up
如果我被抓到偷东西
Because if I got caught stealing,
即使是像香槟杯这样的小玩意
even something as trivial as a champagne glass,
也会让我丢掉工作
I would've lost my job.
但你最后还是为她偷来了  不是吗
But you stole it for her anyway, didn't you?
到头来  我愿意为桑迪做任何事情
At the end of the day, I'd do anything for Sadie,
她也清楚
and she knew it.
遇见她的那一刻  她就已经抓住了我的心
She had me wrapped around her finger the moment I met her.
说清楚点  发生了什么
Walk me through it. Tell me what happened.
罗杰喝完了他的香槟后
When Roger was done with his champagne,
我回收了空杯子悄悄递给了桑迪
I retrieved the empty glass and quietly handed it off to Sadie.
-她用那个做什么  -上楼了
- What did she do with it? - Went upstairs.
大概20分钟后我上去
I followed her up like 20 minutes later
想看看她到底要干嘛
to see what was going on.
那时我发现她倒在地上
That's when I found her.
-你把这些都告诉了你的律师吗  - 没错
- And you told all this to your lawyer? - Yes.
但是我原来的公诉人
But my original public defender
手头案子太多
was too overloaded with other cases.
实话说吧  他认为我有罪
And, truth be told, he thought I was guilty.
他还想让我接受检察官的认罪协议
He wanted me to take the A.D.A.'s plea deal.
辛亏卡莱布·布朗接手了
Thank god Caleb Brown took over.
至少他是在为我拼命辩护
At least he's fighting for me.
关着的感觉怎样  囚犯
Yo. How's it hanging, jailbird?
你已经惹恼了助理地检官
You already pissed off the A.D.A.
于是你就想
So, what, you figured,
何不把法官也给惹毛了呢
why the hell not piss off the judge, as well?
没错  你们可以把我弄出去吗
Yeah. Can you guys get me out of here?
早就办好了  法警叫我们接你出来
Already done. Bailiff called us to come get you.
我会查出事情的真相的
I'm gonna figure out what happened.
我保证
I promise.
你是疯了吗
Are you out of your mind?
我又没做错什么
I didn't do anything wrong.
你忽悠法官推迟庭审
You tricked a judge to postpone a trial,
然后你还非法审问了被告人
and then you illegally questioned the defendant.
对  但除此之外我没做错什么啊
Yeah, but other than that, I didn't do anything wrong.
贝克特  卡塞尔相信妮娜是无辜的了
Yo, Beckett, Castle's convinced that Nina's innocent now.
因为什么
Because why?
就因为桑迪想要罗杰的杯子吗
Because Sadie wanted Roger's glass?
我认为她是想收集他的DNA
I think she was after his DNA.
为什么
Why?
罗杰当她的摄影师20年了
Roger was her cameraman for 20 years.
妮娜说桑迪和男人有过外遇
Nina said that Sadie had had affairs with men in the past.
或许他们确实存在这种关系
Maybe they had had one,
那么桑迪的女儿实际是罗杰的
and Sadie's daughter was actually Roger's.
所以你认为桑迪搞出了整件事情
So, uh, what, you think that Sadie cooked this whole thing up
这样她能得到样本去做亲子鉴定吗
So she could get a DNA sample for a paternity test?
只有一个法子知道真相了
Only one way to find out.
你想让我们去吗  警监
What do you want us to do, Captain?
-我  -贝克特  快看
- I -- - Beckett. Look.
去和罗杰谈吧  看他知道些什么
Uh, go talk to Roger, see what he knows.
他来这儿干嘛
What is he doing here?
我来处理  你自然点
I'll handle this. You just be normal.
警监  你越线了
Captain, you crossed the line.
我知道你让卡塞尔偷偷去问讯了我的客户
I know that you had Castle go in and interview my client --
听着  律师  卡塞尔和我已经分居了
Look, Counselor, Castle and I are separated.
他已不隶属于12分局
He is no longer associated with the 12th precinct.
所以不管是我还是纽约警局
So neither I nor the NYPD
都无需对他的行为负责
can be held accountable for his actions.
所以你根本就不知道吗
So you knew nothing about it?
这就是我说的意思  不是吗
That's what I said, isn't it?
我不相信你
I don't believe you.
我不在乎
And I don't care.
典型的警察风格
Typical cop.
等等
Wait.
干嘛
What?
听着  如果你重申我接下来说的话
Look, if you repeat what I'm about to tell you,
我会否认的
I will deny it.
我让人去调查妮娜的案子了
I have people looking into Nina's case.
你相信她是无辜的吗
Do you believe that she's innocent?
我可没说  但我认为我们必须要弄清楚
I didn't say that, but I think we have to be thorough.
既然庭审被推迟了
And now that the trial has been postponed,
我们有时间进行下一步调查
We have time to investigate further.
我很感谢  警监
I appreciate that, Captain.
律师  妮娜直到昨晨都还不是你的客户
Counselor, Nina wasn't your client until yesterday morning.
为什么你对这个案子这么上心
Why are you so passionate about this case?
我猜是和你一样原因
For the same reason that I assume you are.
公正
Justice.
我是卡莱布·布朗
This is Caleb Brown.
好的
Yes.
怎么
Yeah?
好的  我马上过去
Yeah. Yeah, I'm on my way.
在法官赶回自己家的时候
So, while the judge was heading home,
打电话给邻居  让其帮忙查看自己的房子
She called a neighbor, who checked on her house.
结果房子根本没被盗窃
Turns out, the house was not burglarized.
总之  法官准备一个半小时之后开庭
Anyway, she's ordered that the trial resume in a half an hour.
如果你的人想帮忙证明妮娜的清白
So if your people are going to help prove nina's innocence,
他们最好快点
they'd better hurry.
又是你
You again.
你好  罗杰  我们得谈谈
Hello, Roger. We need to talk.
又怎么了
Now what?
乔安娜
Joanna.
你好
Well, hello!
抱歉突然来访  我们不会打扰太久的
Sorry for the interruption. This won't take long.
确实耽搁不了  庭审马上就要开始了
It actually can't. Trial's gonna start again in a few minutes.
我们必须确认真正的凶手是谁
And we need to nail down who the real killer is
在无辜者被定罪之前
before an innocent woman gets convicted.
你说谁是无辜的  你看到她杀了桑迪
What do you mean innocent? You saw that woman kill Sadie.
不  罗杰  我只是以为我看到了
No, Roger, I only thought I did.
你看  头脑是个有趣的东西
You see, the mind is a funny thing.
不像一个空的容器  它填补空白
Doesn't like a vacuum. So it fills in the blanks.
就像当我发现桑迪和妮娜的恋爱关系时
Much like when I discovered Sadie and Nina were having an affair,
我自然地以为妮娜和恋人吵架后杀了她
I automatically assumed Nina killed her in a lover's quarrel
而实际上她们两个人一起
When really the two of them were working together
想从你那里拿些什么  罗杰
to get something from you, Roger.
他在说些什么
What is he talking about?
我也不知道
I'm sure I have no idea.
-我能补充吗  -请吧
- May I? - Please.
桑迪要妮娜带一个玻璃杯给她
Turns out that Sadie asked Nina to bring her a glass
上面附着你的DNA
with your DNA on it.
问题就是为什么要这么做
The question is why.
-该我说了  -上吧
- My turn? - Go for it.
我们认为你和桑迪有过外遇
We think that you were having an affair with Sadie.
我就知道
I knew it!
这么多年你们俩在一起工作
All those years you were working together,
你们那些秘密的小情话
Your little secret conversations.
你一直都背着我在偷腥  是吧
You were cheating on me this whole time, weren't you?
亲爱的这不是真的  我发誓
Honey, it's not true. I swear.
桑迪想要你DNA的样本
See, Sadie wanted a sample of your DNA
好证明你就是桑迪女儿的父亲
to prove that you are the father of Sadie's daughter.
天呐  看在上帝的份上
Oh, for the love of god.
-我早跟你说了  -我没有明白
- I told you. - I don't understand.
罗杰他不能生育
Roger is infertile...
因为小时候的一次疾病  桑迪也知道
Due to a childhood illness, and Sadie knew that.
说不定连邮差也知道这件事
Hell, the mailman probably knows it,
鉴于罗杰对此事不停嘴
given how much Roger talks about it.
那次经历非常痛苦
It was a very traumatic experience.
事已至此  我想请你们离开
As is this. I'd like you to leave.
抱歉  罗杰  不行
Sorry, Roger. No can do.
桑迪想要你的杯子
Sadie wanted your glass.
如果不为DNA  那她想要什么
If not for DNA, then why?
可能是指纹
Perhaps a fingerprint.
桑迪为什么需要他的指纹
Why would Sadie need his fingerprint?
我不知道
I have no idea.
你妻子知道
Your wife does.
就在那儿  那幅画后面
Right over there. Behind the picture.
乔安娜  你怎么能这样
Joanna, how could you?
拜托  我多年来都一直想知道
Oh, please, I've been dying to know what you've been hiding
你的保险箱里藏着什么  罗杰
in your safe for years now, Roger.
就算你没把桑迪搞怀孕
And the fact that you didn't knock up Sadie
也不代表你没和其他女人乱搞
doesn't mean you weren't knocking boots.
没有搜查令我是绝对不会打开它的
If you think I'm opening that without a warrant, you're crazy.
拿到搜查令需要多长时间
How long would it take to get us a warrant?
一两个小时
An hour or two.
我们没那个时间了
We don't have that kind of time.
乔安娜  你是"妮奇·希特"系列的粉丝吧
Joanna, you're a fan of Nikki Heat.
那又怎样
Yeah, so?
我下一本书的主角
So, how would you like to have
就叫你的名字  你觉得如何
a main character named after you in my next book?
乔安娜  你敢
Joanna, don't you dare.
写成大反派怎么样
How about a villain?
成交
Deal.
你不会的
You wouldn't.
这录像带上有什么  罗杰
What are we gonna find on this tape, Roger?
他们说就是这儿  对吧
Said it's here, right?
对  但你知道他们会撒谎
Yeah, but you know how they lie.
我有所发现
Here. Found something.
可别告诉我是大规模杀伤性武器
Tell me that's not a WMD.
-你知道那是什么  -嗯
- You know what that is? - Yeah.
中情局在伊拉克分发的
One of the $5-million duffel bags
装着五百万美元的旅行袋之一
the CIA's handing out all over Iraq.
我们把它拿走吧
Let's take it.
什么  不
What? No.
桑迪  别这样
Sadie, come on.
这可是五百万  没人会注意到的
It's 5 million bucks, and no one's ever gonna miss it.
罗杰  别想了  我们是记者不是贼
Roger, forget about it. We're reporters, not thieves.
等回到基地我就通知联合特种作战司令部
I'll notify JSOC when we get back to base.
好了  我们出去吧
All right, let's get out of here.
但你们没丢下它  是吧
But you didn't leave it, did you?
看录像带就知道我们丢下它了
You can see on the tape that we did.
对  你一停止录像
Sure, and then once you stopped recording,
就回去拿它
you went back to get it.
在伊拉克战争期间
Over a billion dollars in cash went missing
超过十亿现金不翼而飞
during the Iraq invasion.
区区五百万又算得上什么
What's a lousy $5 mil?
你放不下  是不是
You couldn't just leave it, could you?
不  我确实把它丢在那儿了
Yeah, that's exactly what I did.
只不过桑迪没有  是不是
Except Sadie didn't, did she?
对  她没有
No. She didn't.
她溜回去  独自拿走了那些钱
She snuck back and took it for herself,
然后把钱偷运回美国  想把我排除在外
and then she smuggled it to the States, tried to cut me out.
但你有录像带  你用它勒索她
But you had the tape, and you used that
这样你也能拿到你的那份
to blackmail her so you could get your share.
但桑迪不想让你攥住把柄
But Sadie didn't like you having all that leverage.
我想不通的是
What I can't figure out is,
桑迪夺回录像带  怎么花了这么久
what took Sadie so long to try to get this tape back from you?
我明白了  桑迪之前给过你一笔钱
Oh, I get it. You burned through the money
你挥霍光了  所以还想要更多
that Sadie gave you originally, so you needed more.
我欠下的债都堆成山了
I am mortgaged to the hilt, okay?
所有信用卡都透支了  我妻子还不停地花
All my credit cards are maxed, and my wife won't stop spending.
她在慈善拍卖会上花掉了一万五千多
Hell, she forked over 15 g's to that stupid charity auction.
就为了听伟大的理查德·卡塞尔
To have the great Richard Castle
朗读他小说中的几章
read a couple of chapters out of his novel.
所以你去找桑迪要更多钱
Okay, so you went to Sadie demanding more money,
她拒绝了  那天晚上你抓到她
she refused, and then when you caught her in your office
潜入你的办公室  想要拿走你的东西
that night trying to take what was yours --
你抄起拨火棍  杀了她
You grabbed the fireplace poker and you killed her.
不  你们在我家出现之前
No! I didn't even know Sadie was trying to steal the tape
我都不知道桑迪想偷录像带
until you guys showed up at my house earlier.
那就证明一下  谋杀发生时你在哪儿
Prove it. Where were you at the time of the murder?
你们保证别告诉我妻子
Do you promise not to tell my wife?
我当时在地下室里
I was in the basement
跟奇普·埃文斯和莱斯特·戴维斯一起吸大麻
getting baked with Chip Evans and Lester Davis.
我撒谎是因为我向妻子保证不再吸毒了
I lied because I promised my wife that I would stop toking.
我最近压力很大
It's just... I'm under a lot of stress lately.
告诉我你破案了
Please tell me you solved it.
罗杰的不在场证明成立
Roger's alibi checks out.
我们又回到原点而且毫无头绪
We're back to square one with zero leads.
维勒那边有什么进展吗
Any luck with Weller?
他一心想让她被定罪
All he cares about is getting a conviction,
从陪审团得知妮娜和桑迪的关系后
and from the look of the jury when they found out
的表情判断  他会成功的
about Nina and Sadie's affair, he's gonna get it.
我们得想出个办法来
We need to figure something out.
我有个主意
I have an idea.
卡塞尔  你要干什么
Castle, what are you doing?
拯救无辜女人的性命
Saving an innocent woman's life.
-布朗先生  你的目击者  -停止审判
- Mr. Brown, your witness. - Stop the trial!
好吧  现在怎么办
Okay, so...now what?
我不知道  我没考虑这之后怎么做
I don't know. I didn't think this one all the way through.
法官阁下  你好  很高兴再次见到你
Hello, your honor. Nice to see you again.
你想再进一次拘留所吗  卡塞尔先生
Hoping to make another visit to the holding cells, Mr. Castle?
不  法官阁下  进过一次就够了  谢谢
No, your honor. Once was plenty, thank you.
我为打断您而致以诚挚歉意
And my sincerest apologies for the interruption.
然而  案情有进一步进展
However, there has been a development in the case.
抱歉  法官阁下
Excuse us, your honor,
辩方律师想让目击者出庭作证
but the defense has a witness to call to the stand.
法官阁下  辩方律师想让
Uh, your honor, the defense would like to call
理查德·卡塞尔出庭作证
Richard Castle to the stand.
肯定不是妮娜干的
So, Nina definitely didn't do it.
说点我不知道的东西  比如是谁干的
Tell me something I don't know, like who did.
不知道
No idea.
你发誓你说的是事实  完全真实
Do you swear to tell the truth, the whole truth,
-绝对真实  -我发誓
- and nothing but the truth? - I do.
看来最后我真的再来一次了
Looks like I got my do-over after all.
卡塞尔先生  昨天你作证说
Mr. Castle, yesterday, you testified
我的委托人因杀死比克曼太太而有罪
that my client was guilty of killing Mrs. Beakman.
你还相信那是真的吗
Do you still believe that's true?
不  妮娜是清白的
No. Nina's innocent.
好  那我再问你
Okay, and when, may I ask,
你什么时候改变了对我委托人的看法
did you change your mind about my client?
我意识到妮娜是受害者
When I realized that Nina was a victim.
不凑巧的受害者
Victim of bad timing.
首先是我自己不凑巧
First and foremost, my own.
你说不凑巧
Bad timing, you say?
我不凑巧
It was my bad timing
抵达犯罪现场已经太晚了
that brought me to the crime scene too late.
如果当时我早点到那儿
Had I gotten there earlier,
我就会看见妮娜发现桑迪已经遇刺
I would've seen Nina finding Sadie already stabbed.
好  但我的委托人逃跑了
Okay, but then my client ran.
-为什么  -因为她知道这看起来是什么样
- Why? - Because she knew how it looked.
既然我们说到不凑巧
While we're on the topic of bad timing,
那就别忘了提一下
let's not fail to mention the timing
原来指派给妮娜的公设辩护律师
of Nina originally being paired with a public defender
完全不在乎事情真相  不像你  先生
who didn't care about the truth, unlike you, sir.
卡塞尔先生  有没有其他事
Um...well, Mr. Castle, is there anything --
-你想对法庭说的吗  -有
- is there anything else you'd like to share with the court? - Yes.
尊敬的陪审团  想想真是可怕
Good people of the jury, it is frightening to think about,
妮娜·奥基弗今天受审
but Nina O'keefe is on trial today
仅仅是因为我需要上洗手间
simply because I needed to use the restroom
而楼下的那个
and the one downstairs...
不凑巧
Bad timing.
楼下的洗手间有人
The bathroom downstairs was occupied.
打911
Call 911!
我冲到房子后面
I was rushing through to the back of the house,
以为妮娜是凶手而她在逃跑
thinking Nina was the killer and that she was getting away,
但是真正的凶手根本没有离开
but the true killer never left.
真正的凶手
The true killer...
还在那个洗手间里  清理他穿过后院
was still in that bathroom, cleaning the mud from his shoes,
往返杀害桑迪时
the mud he collected trudging through the backyard...
沾到鞋上的泥
...to and from killing Sadie.
卡塞尔先生  你看到这个人了吗
Mr. Castle, did you see this man?
看到了  说起不凑巧
Yeah. Talk about bad timing.
他出来的时候我刚好看到他
He came out just in time for me to catch him.
你能在法庭上指出这个人吗
Can you point to this man in this courtroom?
那个杀死桑迪·比克曼的凶手
The man who killed Sadie Beakman?
是的  我可以
Yes, I can.
就是她的丈夫  罗伊德·比克曼
It was her husband, Lloyd Beakman.
胡说八道
How dare you.
等等  你和妈妈同时在派对上消失的
Wait, you and mom disappeared from the party at the same time.
我记得是因为我当时试图找你们
No, I-I remember because I was trying to find you guys.
好了  够了  肃静
All right, that's enough. I want order.
很抱歉打扰庭审  法官阁下
Apologies to the court, Your Honor.
乔安娜·马特斯以为桑迪
Joanna Masters thought that Sadie
和她的丈夫罗杰有染
was having an affair with her husband, Roger,
但是她错了  你也一样
but she was wrong, and so were you.
我完全不知道你在说什么
I have absolutely no idea what you're talking about.
你当然知道
Sure, you do.
你看见你的妻子向楼梯上走去
You saw your wife head up those stairs.
你很怀疑  她以前出过轨
You had your suspicions. She had cheated on you before.
所以你走到院子里
So you headed out to the yard,
把篮球框挪过去
you moved the basketball hoop over
这样你就能爬上去看个清楚
so you could climb up it and get a better look.
但是桑迪发现你在窗户上偷看  对不对
But Sadie caught you spying in the window, didn't she?
所以你爬进去
So you came inside
指责她和罗杰有染
and accused her of having an affair with Roger.
爸爸  你做了什么
Dad, what did you do?
我做了什么
What did I do?
你妈妈红杏出墙  还是和她
Your mother was having an affair with... her, of all people.
而你妈妈觉得我一直以为是罗杰真是太好笑了
And it was so funny to your mother that I assumed it was Roger.
她简直乐不可支
She laughed and laughed.
所以你的确和桑迪在楼上
So you were upstairs with Sadie.
我  我的意思是
W-w-w-what I meant was --
发生了什么  罗伊德  你失去理智了吗
What happened, Lloyd? Did you lose control?
那就是你杀她的原因吗
Is that why you killed her?
我不是故意的  我没想杀她
I didn't mean to. I didn't mean it.
我爱桑迪  可我只是
I loved Sadie, but I just --
比克曼先生  我建议你
Mr. Beakman, my advice to you
住嘴然后给自己找一个律师
would be to stop talking and find yourself an attorney.
比克曼先生  你因为谋杀被捕了
Mr. Beakman, you're under arrest for murder.
来吧  伸手
Come on. Hands.
法官阁下  介于案情的发展
Your Honor, in light of these developments,
检察院请求撤销
the people file a motion to dismiss all charges
对妮娜·奥基弗的全部指控
against Nina O'keefe.
同意  案件不予受理
Granted. Case dismissed.
谢谢你
Thank you.
干得漂亮  伙计们  你们应该为自己感到骄傲
Great job, guys. You should be proud of yourselves.
-为什么  我们搞砸了  -是啊
- Why? We blew it. - Yeah.
我们让一个无辜的女人在监狱里呆了五个月
For five months, we had an innocent woman rotting in jail.
不  那不是我们的错
No, that one's not on us.
这是妮娜原来的辩护律师的错
Nina's original defense attorney did that to her.
到最后  是我们还她公道
At the end of the day, we're the ones who brought her justice.
说起这个  我得收回
Speaking of which, I got to take back
我所有说过的辩护律师的坏话
everything bad I've ever said about defense attorneys.
那个卡莱布·布朗  他是好样的
That guy Caleb Brown, he's all right.
是啊  他是个有担当的人
Yeah. He's a stand-up guy.
-回头见  贝克特  -回见
- We'll see you later, Beckett. - Yeah.
晚安   伙计们
Okay, goodnight, guys.
卡莱布是个"有担当的人"  如果他们知道
Caleb's a "Stand-up guy." If they only knew.
不  他们说的没错
No, they're right.
我是说  卡莱布是恶魔  但我们今天看到的是
I mean, Caleb is a monster, but what we learned today
他是一个极尽所能为善的恶魔
is that he is a monster who is desperate to do good.
所以呢
So?
所以我们一直在寻找他的弱点
So, we were looking for his weakness.
我们找到了
And we just found it.
庆祝的香槟
Hey. Celebratory champagne.
觉得非常合适  介于它在今天
Felt appropriate, given the twist it played
审判室戏剧中起到的反转
in today's courtroom drama.
是啊  足够撑起一部法律恐怖片
Yes, enough drama to fill a legal thriller.
也许你应该换个路线
Maybe you should try a new genre.
也许我应该努力不要再出庭作证
Maybe I should try to make sure I never testify in court again.
你让一个无辜的女人重获自由  里克
You kept an innocent woman out of jail, Rick.
我为你感到骄傲
I'm proud of you for that.
如果没有你我肯定做不到
Couldn't have done it without you.
你们洛克塞特的调查进展如何
How is your investigation into LokSat coming along?
你知道我不能告诉你这个
You know I can't tell you about that.
好吧  为了我的安全
Right, right. For my own safety.
但是我可以告诉你
Uh... but I can tell you this.
我快查到了
I'm getting close.
很好  因为我也快了
That's good, because so am I.
明晚8点中部时间7点《单身汉》与您相约
Find love with Bachelor tomorrow at 8/7 central.
我爱死你的书了
I love your books.
卡塞尔有了"新恋情"
There's more romance for Castle,
里克遇到忠粉  一个有危险企图的忠粉
when Rick meets a really big fan, with some dangerous intention.
全新《灵书妙探》联播
The all new Castle double date event
明日晚10点中部时间9点ABC台精彩继续
continues tomorrow 10/9 c on ABC.